What Happens In Antarctica... Stays in Antarctica
Farce of the Penguins is a comedy, romance,
documentary film directed by Bob Saget.
In this spoof of "March of the Penguins," nature footage of penguins
near the South Pole gets a soundtrack of human voices.
Carl and Jimmy, best friends, walk 70 miles to the mating
grounds where the female penguins wait.
The huddled masses of females - especially Melissa and Vicki - talk
about males, mating, and what might happen this year.
Carl, Jimmy, and the other males make the long trek
talking about food, fornication and flatulence.
Until this year, Carl's sex life has been dismal, but he falls hard for Melissa.
She seems to like him.
A crisis develops when Jimmy comes upon something soft in the dark.
Can friends forgive?
Does parenthood await Carl and Melissa?
Narrador (voz), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Hottie Penguin (voz), played by Alyson Hannigan.
Carl (voz), played by Bob Saget.
I Need a Z-Pack Penguin (voz), played by Brie Larson.
Juan Sanchez (voz), played by Carlos Mencia.
There's No Snow Penguin (voz), played by Dave Coulier.
March of the Penguins (French: La Marche de l'empereur; French pronunciation: [lamaʁʃ
dəlɑ̃ˈpʁœʁ]) is a 2005 French nature documentary film directed and written by Luc Jacquet.
The documentary depicts the yearly journey of the
emperor penguins of Antarctica.
In autumn, all the penguins of breeding age (five years old and over) leave the ocean, which
is their normal habitat, to walk inland to their ancestral breeding grounds.
There, the penguins participate in a courtship that, if
successful, results in the hatching of a chick.
For the chick to survive, both parents must make multiple arduous journeys
between the ocean and the breeding grounds over the ensuing months.
It took one year for the two isolated cinematographers Laurent Chalet and Jérôme Maison to shoot the
documentary, which was shot around the French scientific base of Dumont d'Urville in Adélie Land.
March of the Penguins was released in France on 26 January
2005 by Buena Vista International France.
The documentary won the 2006 Academy Awards for Best Documentary Feature.
On 1 June 2010, a home video release in France included
the film in the Disneynature collection.
It is named as one of the most successful
documentaries in North America and France.
A direct sequel titled March of the Penguins 2: The Next Step
was released in France in 2017 by Disneynature.
The film explores themes of penguin, mockumentary,
balzen, antarctica, found footage.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.